

## **RANKING**

REPEC World Last 10 Yrs.¹ 104-th

REPEC World All Yrs.² Top %2,25

Web of Science h-index³ 26

REPEC-CitEc h-index⁴ 23

SCOPUS h-index⁵ 27

Google Scholar h-index⁶ 37

ResearchGate Score² 37,74

## **CONTACT**

- Emek Mh., Kazakistan Cd., No: 64/4, Cankaya, Ankara 06490, Turkey
- +90 532 396-0145, +90 548 874-0356
- mehmet@mbalcilar.net
- http://www.mbalcilar.net



- <sup>1</sup> On 2021-07-22, among 62.443 registered economists. See REPEC IDEAS ID: pba722.
- <sup>2</sup> On 2021-07-22, among 62.443 registered economists. See REPEC IDEAS ID: pba722.
- <sup>3</sup> On 2021-07-22, See Web of Science Researcher ID K-7346-2019.
- <sup>4</sup> On 2021-07-22, See CitEc Citation Profile ID: pba722.
- <sup>5</sup> On 2021-07-22, See SCOPUS Author ID 55921038200.
- <sup>6</sup> On 2021-07-22, See Google Scholar ID iNbxXPkAA-AAI&hl
- On 2021-07-22, See ResearchGate Profile Mehmet Balcilar.

# **MEHMET BALCILAR**

**Economist & Data Scientist** 

# **PROFILE**

Mehmet Balcilar currently works as professor and head of the Department of Economics at Eastern Mediterrenean University located in North Cyprus. He is also an extraordinary professor at University of Pretoria in South Africa, affiliated professor at Montepellier Business School in France, and research fellow at Economic Research Forum in Egypt. He also frequently serves as advisor and consultant to various institutions, including the World Bank and World Health Organization, on data science, risk analysis, statistics, economics, and field surveys.

His main research areas include macroeconomics, risk analysis, econometrics, time series analysis, nonparametric statistics, health economics, and transition economies.

## **EDUCATION**

Ph.D.	Wayne State University (US)	Economics/Econometrics	1996
MA	Cleveland State University (US)	Applied Economics	1991
MA	Çukurova University (Turkey)	Economics	1990
BA	Dokuz Eylül University (Turkey)	Tourism Management	1986

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Education and research:** Wayne State University (US, 3 years, 1993-96), University of Pretoria (South Africa, 5 months, 2013-19), Montepellier Business School (France, 1 month, 2018), Kyrgyz-Turkish Manas University (Kyrgyzstan, 3 years, 2001-04), KIMEP University (Kazakhstan, 1 year, 2004-05), Cukurova University (Turkey, 8 years, 1986-90,1996-01, 2005-07), Eastern Mediterrenean University (KKTC, 13 year, 2009-Present).

Advisor, consultant, researcher: World Bank (WB), World Health Organization (WHO), OCHA, UNICEF, Procter & Gamble, Standing Committee for Economic and Commercial Cooperation of the Organization of the Islamic Cooperation (COMCEC), Republic of Turkey Nicosia Embassy Development and Cooperation Office (DCO), Republic of Turkey Ministry of Health, Turkish Aerospace Industries (TAI), Republic of Turkey Undersecretary of the Prime Ministry, Republic of Turkey Disaster and Emergency Management Authority, Republic of Turkey State Planning Organization, Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey (TUBITAK).

# **ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES**

#### **Publications:**

SCIE and SSCI journals:	148	SCOPUS journals:	20
Other peer reviewed journals:	12	Proceedings:	32
Book chapters:	5	Research/project reports:	33
Conference presentations:	72	Book translations:	3

#### Other academic activities:

Ph.D. supervision: 21 Master's supervision: 13

Conference and workshop organizations: 17

Seminar, summer school, and workshops for academicians: 35

Research and publication awards: 13

Research projects and grants: 35

**Citations:** Web of Science: 2,546 | SCOPUS: 2,935 | REPEC: 2,114 | ResearchGate: 4,428 | Google Scholar: 6,066 (as of 2021-07-23 ).